{
  "title": "5.3",
  "definitions": {
    "CONCUR": {
      "word": "CONCUR",
      "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-ker')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to agree; to happen together </p><p>To CONCUR with someone is to agree with him, to have the same opinion as he does. </p><p>“Everyone CONCURRED that this was the only action that could be taken.” </p><p>“The two of us did not CONCUR in our opinion of the movie.” </p><p>CONCUR can also mean “to happen or work together.” </p><p>“His father’s death and his accident CONCURRED, making it impossible for him to start college this semester.” </p><p>The noun from CONCUR is CONCURRENCE, which means <i class=“def-ital\">agreement.</i> </p><p>“With her parents’ CONCURRENCE she decided to take a year off from school.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONCURRENCE, n. CONCURRENT, adj.</p>"
    },
    "INITIAL": {
      "word": "INITIAL",
      "phonetic": "(i-ni'-shÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">beginning, first </p><p>INITIAL comes from a Latin word meaning <i class=“def-ital\">beginning.</i> This is also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">initiate,</i> which means to <i class=“def-ital\">begin, set going.</i> INITIAL means “of or at the beginning.” </p><p>“My INITIAL feeling was that he was being unfair, but later I changed my mind.” </p><p>“His INITIAL act as king was to release all the political prisoners.” </p><p>“INITIALLY we opposed the idea, but now we are in favor of it.” </p><p>INITIALS are the beginning letters of names. </p><p>“The INITIALS ‘U.S.A.’ stand for the United States of America.”</p>"
    },
    "ABDUCT": {
      "word": "ABDUCT",
      "phonetic": "(ab-duhkt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to kidnap, carry off </p><p>To ABDUCT a person is to carry him off by force and illegally, to <i class=“def-ital\">kidnap</i> him. </p><p>“Two men ABDUCTED the child and held him for ransom.” </p><p>“The rich businessman was ABDUCTED yesterday by three masked men.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Harm</i> is often chosen as the meaning of ABDUCT in the Pretest. A person who is ABDUCTED may also be <i class=“def-ital\">harmed,</i> but ABDUCT means only to <i class=“def-ital\">kidnap.</i> Other forms of the word: ABDUCTION, n.</p>"
    },
    "ADVERSARY": {
      "word": "ADVERSARY",
      "phonetic": "(ad'-vÔøΩr-ser-E)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an enemy, opponent </p><p>An ADVERSARY is an enemy or opponent, someone you fight with or have a contest with. </p><p>“Those two hated each other from the day they met, and they’ve been ADVERSARIES ever since.” </p><p>“Try to be nicer to people; don’t act as if everyone were your ADVERSARY.” </p><p>“Although the two lawyers often were ADVERSARIES in court, they were the best of friends otherwise.” </p><p>People often think an ADVERSARY is a partner, which is almost opposite in meaning.</p>"
    },
    "SABER": {
      "word": "SABER",
      "phonetic": "(sA'-bÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a sword </p><p>A SABER is a heavy military sword with a curved blade. It is also a fencing or dueling sword. </p><p>“The officer swung his SABER at the advancing enemy.” </p><p>“He stood at attention before the general, his SABER at his side.” </p><p>“SABER rattling” is a threatening display of military power of any kind. </p><p>“The enemy put thousands of troops on our borders and made insulting speeches about us. This SABER rattling didn’t bother us a bit.’’</p>"
    },
    "ARID": {
      "word": "ARID",
      "phonetic": "(ar'-ÔøΩd)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">dry, barren, parched </p><p>ARID means “without moisture,” <i class=“def-ital\">dry.</i> ARID is usually a somewhat stronger word than <i class=“def-ital\">dry.</i> Something that is ARID is totally dry and lifeless. When used about land, the word means specifically “without enough rainfall to grow crops.” </p><p>“Farmers couldn’t survive in the ARID regions of the West.” </p><p>ARID can also be used in a general sense to mean <i class=“def-ital\">lifeless, barren, monotonous.</i> </p><p>“The book’s treatment of history was rather ARID—it was just a listing of dates and names.” </p><p>“She fell asleep during the ARID discussion of the rules for the meeting.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ARIDITY, n.</p>"
    },
    "CASCADE": {
      "word": "CASCADE",
      "phonetic": "(kas-kAd')",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a waterfall </p><p>A CASCADE is a fall of water over steep, slanted rocks, as in a river or stream. It is not just a straight fall of water but one that is broken up into a series of stages or steps. </p><p>“Halfway up the mountain we came upon a CASCADE of clear water that rushed over a series of jagged rocks high above us.” </p><p>CASCADE can be used about anything that falls or rushes forth in great quantity. </p><p>“The end of the symphony was truly magnificent, with its CASCADE of sound filling every corner of the huge auditorium.” </p><p>CASCADE can also be used as a verb meaning “to fall or pour down as if in a waterfall.” </p><p>“Yards of gorgeous lace CASCADED down the front of the bridal gown.”</p>"
    },
    "DILIGENT": {
      "word": "DILIGENT",
      "phonetic": "(dil'-ÔøΩjÔøΩnt)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">hard-working, industrious, tireless </p><p>Someone who is DILIGENT works hard and carefully at something. He doesn’t let up or make silly mistakes. </p><p>“We will only hire DILIGENT employees. We want people who will put in a good day’s work.” </p><p>“They searched DILIGENTLY for the lost ring all day, but finally had to give up.” </p><p>“The DILIGENT student did his homework faithfully every night.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: DILIGENCE, n.</p>"
    },
    "ACCUSATION": {
      "word": "ACCUSATION",
      "phonetic": "(ak-yU-zA'-shJn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a charge </p><p>To ACCUSE a person is to declare that he is guilty of having done something wrong or evil, to charge him with something. </p><p>“The teacher ACCUSED him of stealing the watch.” </p><p>“I was ACCUSED of being one of the gang.” </p><p>If you are ACCUSED of a crime, it doesn’t mean you are guilty. It just means someone thinks you are guilty. </p><p>ACCUSATION is the noun from ACCUSE. It is a <i class=“def-ital\">charge,</i> a declaration of wrongdoing. </p><p>“There was an ACCUSATION in the newspaper that the mayor had accepted a bribe.” </p><p>“He denied all the ACCUSATIONS against him.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ACCUSE, v.</p>"
    },
    "MEANDER": {
      "word": "MEANDER",
      "phonetic": "(mE-an'-dÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to wander, ramble, follow a winding course </p><p>The MEANDER was a river in ancient Asia noted for its winding course. As a verb, MEANDER means to <i class=“def-ital\">wander aimlessly,</i> without a destination. The word can be used about people, and about things like roads or rivers. </p><p>“The path MEANDERED through the forest.” </p><p>“After dinner they MEANDERED through the park for a while.” </p><p>“He MEANDERED from town to town, heading nowhere in particular.”</p>"
    },
    "ENCOMPASS": {
      "word": "ENCOMPASS",
      "phonetic": "(en-kuhm'-pÔøΩs)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to include, surround, encircle, envelop </p><p>One meaning of COMPASS is <i class=“def-ital\">limits</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">boundaries.</i> </p><p>“This subject is well within the COMPASS of our study.” </p><p>To ENCOMPASS something is to include it within a particular COMPASS, to <i class=“def-ital\">encircle</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">enclose</i> it. </p><p>“These mountains ENCOMPASS the valley.” </p><p>“This book ENCOMPASSES the entire history of opera\"—that is, the entire history is included in the book. </p><p>“The study of art ENCOMPASSES painting, drawing, and sculpture.”</p>"
    },
    "EMBRYONIC": {
      "word": "EMBRYONIC",
      "phonetic": "(em-brE-on'-ik)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">undeveloped, immature, rudimentary </p><p>An EMBRYO is an animal in the early stages of its development before birth. The adjective from EMBRYO is EMBRYONIC, which means “like an EMBRYO.”  Since an EMBRYO is very young and undeveloped, EMBRYONIC can apply to anything which is in its earliest stages, which hasn’t developed enough to be recognizable. Just as an EMBRYO turns into a mature adult, something which is called EMBRYONIC should be capable of developing into something much larger and more complete. </p><p>“The plans are still EMBRYONIC: it will take us a while to complete them.” </p><p>“When the industry was in its EMBRYONIC stages few people realized how important it would become.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EMBRYO, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ic</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "AFFILIATE": {
      "word": "AFFILIATE",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩfil'-E-At)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to ally, associate </p><p>The Latin word <i class=“def-ital\">filius</i> means <i class=“def-ital\">son.</i> AFFILIATE comes from a Latin word which means “to adopt as a son.” In English the word has come to mean “to enter into association” or “to join as a member.” AFFILIATE usually suggests a close relationship, but one in which the various people or parts stay at least somewhat separate. </p><p>“Our team tried to AFFILIATE itself with the local softball league.” </p><p>“He is not AFFILIATED with any company. He works for himself.” </p><p>“The national organization has many local branches AFFILIATED with it.” </p><p>AFFILIATE is also a noun. </p><p>“Channel 3 is an AFFILIATE of the CBS television network.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: AFFILIATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "BISECT": {
      "word": "BISECT",
      "phonetic": "(bl-sekt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to cut in two, halve, split To BISECT something is to cut it into two, usually equal, pieces. The <i class=“def-ital\">bi-</i> part of the word means <i class=“def-ital\">two,</i> as in <i class=“def-ital\">bicycle</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">binoculars</i>. The <i class=“def-ital\">-sect</i> part means <i class=“def-ital\">cut,</i> as in <i class=“def-ital\">dissect</i> (to cut apart) and <i class=“def-ital\">intersect</i> (to cut across). “The new road will BISECT the town neatly, passing right through the center of it.” “The 90° angle was BISECTED to make two 45° angles.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Double</i> is the most common incorrect answer on the Pretest. People who choose it know that <i class=“def-ital\">bi-</i> means <i class=“def-ital\">two,</i> but don’t know its special use in BISECT.</p>"
    },
    "WRETCHED": {
      "word": "WRETCHED",
      "phonetic": "(rech'-ÔøΩd)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">miserable, foul, poor </p><p>A WRETCHED person is very unhappy or unlucky. </p><p>“I felt WRETCHED when I woke up this morning, but now I’m somewhat better.” </p><p>“This WRETCHED woman has had a hard life.” </p><p>A WRETCHED thing is of very poor quality. </p><p>“This book is WRETCHED. It is the worst I’ve ever read.” </p><p>“They live in a WRETCHED shack with no heat or running water.” </p><p>A WRETCH is a miserable person, either one who is very unfortunate or one who is very evil. </p><p>“Those poor WRETCHES are doomed to die very soon.” </p><p>“Some hateful WRETCH thought it would be fun to burn our house down.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: WRETCH, n.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "3",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Will he CONCUR?",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "agree",
            "decide",
            "be there",
            "argue"
          ],
          "word": "CONCUR",
          "correct": "agree"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The INITIAL reports.",
          "answers": [
            "beginning",
            "clever",
            "shortened",
            "final",
            "latest"
          ],
          "word": "INITIAL",
          "correct": "beginning"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ABDUCT her.",
          "answers": [
            "save",
            "admit",
            "threaten",
            "kidnap",
            "harm"
          ],
          "word": "ABDUCT",
          "correct": "kidnap"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His usual ADVERSARY.",
          "answers": [
            "partner",
            "target",
            "messenger",
            "argument",
            "opponent"
          ],
          "word": "ADVERSARY",
          "correct": "opponent"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His SABER.",
          "answers": [
            "armor",
            "spear",
            "sword",
            "cannon",
            "fur"
          ],
          "word": "SABER",
          "correct": "sword"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ARID places.",
          "answers": [
            "dry",
            "rainy",
            "bare",
            "hot",
            "green"
          ],
          "word": "ARID",
          "correct": "dry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Marvelous CASCADE.",
          "answers": [
            "stream",
            "sunbeam",
            "waterfall",
            "mountain",
            "tomb"
          ],
          "word": "CASCADE",
          "correct": "waterfall"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DILIGENT teacher.",
          "answers": [
            "low-paid",
            "strict",
            "careless",
            "wise",
            "hard-working"
          ],
          "word": "DILIGENT",
          "correct": "hard-working"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another ACCUSATION.",
          "answers": [
            "remark",
            "decision",
            "charge",
            "suggestion",
            "problem"
          ],
          "word": "ACCUSATION",
          "correct": "charge"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tendency to MEANDER.",
          "answers": [
            "mumble",
            "wander",
            "dream",
            "sleep",
            "despair"
          ],
          "word": "MEANDER",
          "correct": "wander"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What does it ENCOMPASS?",
          "answers": [
            "point to",
            "leave out",
            "mean",
            "include",
            "matter"
          ],
          "word": "ENCOMPASS",
          "correct": "include"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EMBRYONIC plans.",
          "answers": [
            "exciting",
            "productive",
            "undeveloped",
            "complete",
            "unusual"
          ],
          "word": "EMBRYONIC",
          "correct": "undeveloped"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "No longer AFFILIATED.",
          "answers": [
            "separated",
            "allied",
            "admired",
            "pleased",
            "ashamed"
          ],
          "word": "AFFILIATE",
          "correct": "allied"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BISECT it.",
          "answers": [
            "double",
            "meet",
            "decrease",
            "halve",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "BISECT",
          "correct": "halve"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were WRETCHED.",
          "answers": [
            "captured",
            "alert",
            "soaked",
            "sick",
            "miserable"
          ],
          "word": "WRETCHED",
          "correct": "miserable"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually get upset when someone CONCURS with them?",
          "word": "CONCUR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is December the INITIAL month of the year?",
          "word": "INITIAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it against the law to ABDUCT someone?",
          "word": "ABDUCT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would ADVERSARIES usually help each other?",
          "word": "ADVERSARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you cut someone with a SABER?",
          "word": "SABER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a desert be ARID?",
          "word": "ARID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would molasses CASCADE out of the jar?",
          "word": "CASCADE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are lazy people usually DILIGENT?",
          "word": "DILIGENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are people who are ACCUSED of murder always guilty?",
          "word": "ACCUSATION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do runners usually MEANDER toward the finish line?",
          "word": "MEANDER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does the atmosphere ENCOMPASS the earth?",
          "word": "ENCOMPASS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an EMBRYONIC project be nearly finished?",
          "word": "EMBRYONIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person AFFILIATE himself with a political party?",
          "word": "AFFILIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a river BISECT a city?",
          "word": "BISECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people like to eat WRETCHED food?",
          "word": "WRETCHED",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "No one CONCURRED with Jim's opinion that the earth is flat.",
          "word": "CONCUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their INITIAL findings were supported by later research.",
          "word": "INITIAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jane ABDUCTED to us that we weren't trying hard enough.",
          "word": "ABDUCT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Poor people love this senator because he is their leading ADVERSARY in Congress.",
          "word": "ADVERSARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The scar on his face is the result of a SABER duel.",
          "word": "SABER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone became excited and angry during the ARID debate.",
          "word": "ARID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her long hair fell over her shoulders in beautiful CASCADES.",
          "word": "CASCADE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jane was so DILIGENT we knew that nothing would get done while she was in charge.",
          "word": "DILIGENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was terribly upset by the ACCUSATION that she had lied.",
          "word": "ACCUSATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The speaker MEANDERED us to the point where we were all bored.",
          "word": "MEANDER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He ENCOMPASSED the dog by letting it run free.",
          "word": "ENCOMPASS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His idea was at such an EMBRYONIC stage that we didn't know if it was any good or not.",
          "word": "EMBRYONIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Our organization is not AFFILIATED with any other group.",
          "word": "AFFILIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He BISECTED the pie with a knife.",
          "word": "BISECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "That WRETCH made our lives miserable for years.",
          "word": "WRETCHED",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CONCUR",
          "answers": [
            "agree",
            "consent",
            "expect"
          ],
          "word": "CONCUR",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INITIAL",
          "answers": [
            "recent",
            "first",
            "earliest"
          ],
          "word": "INITIAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABDUCT",
          "answers": [
            "steal",
            "kidnap",
            "chase"
          ],
          "word": "ABDUCT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ADVERSARY",
          "answers": [
            "opponent",
            "soldier",
            "rival"
          ],
          "word": "ADVERSARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SABER",
          "answers": [
            "sword",
            "arrow",
            "blade"
          ],
          "word": "SABER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ARID",
          "answers": [
            "waterless",
            "aged",
            "dull"
          ],
          "word": "ARID",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CASCADE",
          "answers": [
            "fall",
            "pour",
            "fly"
          ],
          "word": "CASCADE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DILIGENT",
          "answers": [
            "careful",
            "busy",
            "slow"
          ],
          "word": "DILIGENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACCUSATION",
          "answers": [
            "blame",
            "admission",
            "criticism"
          ],
          "word": "ACCUSATION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MEANDER",
          "answers": [
            "ramble",
            "search",
            "stray"
          ],
          "word": "MEANDER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCOMPASS",
          "answers": [
            "contain",
            "describe",
            "encircle"
          ],
          "word": "ENCOMPASS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EMBRYONIC",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "small",
            "different"
          ],
          "word": "EMBRYONIC",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AFFILIATE",
          "answers": [
            "remember",
            "join",
            "associate"
          ],
          "word": "AFFILIATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BISECT",
          "answers": [
            "smash",
            "cut",
            "split"
          ],
          "word": "BISECT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "WRETCHED",
          "answers": [
            "unhappy",
            "dumb",
            "disgusting"
          ],
          "word": "WRETCHED",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}